Wait for it.
- Can I turn on the radio?
- No.
Jane, you can't keep doing this.
The last 17 occurrences
have been predictable to the second.
Jane, you're an astrophysicist,
not some storm chaser.
I'm telling you,
there's a connection
between these atmospheric
disturbances and my research.
Erik, I wouldn't have asked you
to fly out here if I wasn't absolutely sure.
Jane?
I think you want to see this.
What is that?
I thought you said
it was a subtle aurora!
Go!
- Get closer.
- Right. Good one.
Go!
What are you doing?
I am not dying for 6 college credits!
I think
that was legally your fault.
Get the first aid Kit.
Do me a favor and don't be dead.
Please.
Where did he come from?
Once,
mankind accepted a simple truth,
that they were not alone
in this universe.
Some worlds man believed
to be home to their gods.
Others, they knew to fear.
From a realm of cold and darkness
came the Frost Giants,
threatening to plunge the mortal world
into a new ice age.
But humanity
would not face this threat alone.
Our armies drove the Frost Giants
back into the heart of their own world.
The cost was great.
In the end,
their king fell.
And the source of their power
was taken from them.
With the last great war ended,
we withdrew from the other worlds
and returned home
to the Realm Eternal,
Asgard
Here we remain as a beacon of hope,
shining out across the stars.
And though we have fallen
into man's myths and legends,
it was Asgard
and its warriors
that brought peace
to the universe.
But the day will come
when one of you
will have to defend that peace.
Do the Frost Giants still live?
When I'm king,
I'll hunt the monsters down
and slay them all!
Just as you did, Father.
A wise king
never seeks out war.
But he must always be ready for it.
- I'm ready, Father.
- So am I.
Only one of you can ascend
to the throne.
But both of you were born to be kings.
Oh, please.
Thor Odinson,
my heir,
my firstborn.
So long entrusted with
the mighty hammer Mjolnir,
forged in the heart of a dying star,
its power has no equal,
as a weapon to destroy
or as a tool to build.
'Tis a fit companion for a king.
I have defended Asgard
and the lives of the innocent
across the Nine Realms
from the time of the great beginning.
Though the day has come...
Do you swear to guard
the Nine Realms?
I swear.
And do you swear
to preserve the peace?
I swear.
Do you swear
to cast aside all selfish ambition
and to pledge yourself only
to the good of the Realms?
I swear!
Then, on this day,
I, Odin Allfather,
proclaim you...
The Frost Giants!
The Jotuns must pay
for what they've done!
They have paid, with their lives.
The Destroyer did its work,
the Casket is safe, and all is well.
All is Well?
They broke into the weapons vault!
If the Frost Giants had stolen
even one of these relics...
- They didn't.
- Well, I want to know why!
I have a truce with Laufey,
King of the Jotuns.
He just broke your truce!
They know you are vulnerable!
What action would you take?
March into Jotunheim as you once did.
Teach them a lesson.
Break their spirits
so they'll never dare
try to cross our borders again.
You're thinking only as a warrior.
This was an act of war!
It was the act of but a few,
doomed to fail.
Look how far they got!
We will find the breach in our defenses
and it will be sealed.
As King of Asgard....
But you're not king!
Not yer.
It's unwise to be in my company
right now, Brother.
This was to be my day of triumph.
It'll come.
In time.
What's this?
If it's any consolation,
I think you're right.
About the Frost Giants,
about Laufey, about everything.
If they found a way to penetrate
Asgard's defenses once,
who's to say they won't try again?
- Next time with an army.
- Exactly.
There's nothing you can do
without defying Father.
No, no, no. I know that look.
That's the only way
to ensure the safety of our borders.
Thor, it's madness.
Madness? What sort of madness?
We're going to Jotunheim.
What?
This isn't like a journey to Earth
where you summon
a little lightning and thunder,
and the mortals worship you as a god.
This is Jotunheim.
My father fought his way into Jotunheim,
defeated their armies
and took their Casket.
We would just be looking for answers.
It is forbidden!
My friends, have you forgotten
all that we have done together?
Fandral, Hogun.
Who led you
into the most glorious of battles?
You did.
And Volstagg,
to delicacies so succulent,
you thought you'd died
and gone to Valhalla?
You did.
Yes!
And who proved wrong
all who scoffed at the idea
that a young maiden could be
one of the fiercest warriors
this realm has ever known?
I did.
True, but I supported you, Sif.
My friends,
we're going to Jotunheim.
You leave this to me.
- Good Heimdall...
- You're not dressed warmly enough.
I'm sorry?
Do you think that you can deceive me?
- You must be mistaken...
- Enough!
Heimdall, may we pass?
Never has an enemy slipped my watch
until this day.
I wish to know how that happened.
Then tell no one where we have gone
until we've returned.
Understand?
What happened?
Silver tongue turn to lead?
Be warned.
I will honor my sworn oath
to protect this realm as its Gatekeeper.
If your return
threatens the safety of Asgard,
Bifrost will remain closed to you
and you'll be left to die
in the cold waste of Jotunheim.
Couldn't you just
leave the bridge open for us?
To leave the bridge open
would unleash
the full power of the Bifrost
and destroy Jotunheim with you upon it.
I have no plans to die today.
None do.
We shouldn't be here.
Let's move.
Where are they?
Hiding,
as cowards always do.
You've come a long way to die,
Asgardians.
I am Thor Odinson!
We know who you are.
How did your people get into Asgarol?
The House of Odin is full of traitors.
Do not dishonor my father's name
with your lies!
Your father is a murderer and a thief!
And why have you come here?
To make peace?
You long for battle. You crave it.
You're nothing but a boy
trying to prove himself a man.
Well, this "boy"
has grown tired of your mockery.
Thor, stop and think.
Look around you, we're outnumbered.
Know your place, Brother.
You know not
what your actions would unleash.
I do.
Go now, while I still allow it.
We will accept your most gracious offer.
Come on, Brother.
Run back home, little princess.
Damn.
Next?
At least make it a challenge for me!
That's more like it.
Don't let them touch you!
Thor!
- We must go!
- Then go!
Run!
Thor!
Heimdall!
Open the bridge!
Father! We'll finish them together!
Silence!
Allfather.
You look weary.
Laufey,
end this now.
Your boy sought this out.
You're right.
And these are the actions of a boy,
treat them as such.
You and I can end this here and now,
before there's further bloodshed.
We are beyond diplomacy now,
Allfather.
He'll get what he came for.
War
and death.
So be it.
Why did you bring us back?
Do you realize what you've done?
- What you've started?
- I was protecting my home.
You cannot even protect your friends!
How can you hope
to protect a kingdom?
Get him to the healing room! Now!
There won't be a kingdom
to protect if you're afraid to act.
The Jotuns must learn to fear me,
just as they once feared you.
That's pride and vanity talking,
not leadership.
You've forgotten everything I taught you
about a warrior's patience.
While you wait and be patient,
the Nine Realms laugh at us.
The old ways are done.
You'd stand giving speeches
while Asgard falls.
You are a vain, greedy, cruel boy!
And you are an old man and a fool!
Yes.
I was a fool
to think you were ready.
Father...
Thor Odinson,
you have betrayed
the express command of your king.
Through your arrogance and stupidity,
you've opened these peaceful realms
and innocent lives
to the horror and desolation of war!
You are unworthy of these realms!
You're unworthy of your title!
You're unworthy
of the loved ones you have betrayed.
I now take from you your power!
In the name of my father
and his father before,
I, Odin Allfather, cast you out!
Whosoever holds this hammer,
if he be worthy,
shall possess the power of Thor.
I think
that was legally your fault.
Get the first aid Kit.
Do me a favor and don't be dead.
Whoa. Does he need CPR?
Because I totally know CPR.
Where did he come from?
You all right?
Hammer?
Yeah, we can tell you're hammered.
It's pretty obvious.
Oh, my God. Erik, look at this!
We have to move quickly
before this all changes.
Jane, we have to take him
to the hospital.
- Father!
- He's fine, look at him.
Heimdall! I know you can hear me!
Open the Bifrost!
Hospital. You go, I'll stay.
You. What realm is this?
Alfheim? Nornheim?
New Mexico?
You dare threaten me, Thor,
with so puny a weapon?
What? He was freaking me out!
Next time
you decide to taser somebody,
make sure he's already in the car, okay?
Jane! Come on.
Name?
He said it was Thor?
T-H-O-R.
- And your relationship to him?
- I've never met him before.
Until she hit him with a car.
I grazed him, but she tasered him.
Yes, I did.
Hi.
Just taking a little blood.
How dare you attack the son of Odin?
I need some help!
Call security!
Security to ER 3, stat!
You're no match for the Mighty...
Huh.
You don't think
this was just a magnetic storm, do you?
Look, the lensing around these edges
is characteristic
of an Einstein-Rosen Bridge.
A what?
- I thought you were a science major?
- Political science.
She was the only applicant.
An Einstein-Rosen Bridge
is a theoretical connection
between two different points
of space-time.
It's a wormhole.
- Erik, look. What do you see?
- Stars.
Yeah, but not our stars.
See, this is the star alignment
for our quadrant this time of year,
and unless Ursa Minor decided
to take a day off,
these are
someone else's constellations.
Hey! Check this out.
No, it can't be.
I think I left something at the hospital.
It's not possible!
He was on drugs or something.
He just went nuts.
Oh, my God.
I just lost
my most important piece of evidence.
Typical.
- So now what?
- We find him.
Did you see what he did in there?
I'm not sure finding him is the best idea.
Well, our data can't tell us
what it was like to be inside that event,
and he can. So, we're gonna find him.
Okay.
So we're gonna look
all over New Mexico, right?
Exactly.
What?
I'm so sorry.
I swear I'm not doing this on purpose.
I got it, I got it.
Come on, kick it in now!
Did it Work?
Sir, we found it.
You know, for a crazy homeless person,
he's pretty cut.
Hey, sorry I tased you!
Excuse me, excuse me!
What is this?
Oh.
My ex.
Good with patients
and bad with relationships.
They're the only clothes I had
that would fit you.
They will suffice.
You're welcome.
This mortal form has grown weak.
I need sustenance.
We should never have let him go.
There was no stopping him.
Well, at least
he's only banished, not dead.
Which is what we'd all be
if that guard hadn't told Odin
where we'd gone.
How did the guard even know?
I told him.
What?
I told him to go to Odin after we'd left.
He should be flogged for taking so long.
We should never have
reached Jotunheim.
You told the guard?
I saved our lives.
And Thor's.
I had no idea Father would banish him
for what he did.
Loki.
You must go to the Allfather
and convince him to change his mind.
And if I do, then what?
I love Thor more dearly than any of you,
but you know what he is.
He's arrogant.
He's reckless. He's dangerous.
You saw how he was today.
Is that what Asgard needs from its king?
He may speak of the good of Asgard,
but he's always been jealous of Thor.
We should be grateful to him,
he saved our lives.
Laufey said
there were traitors in the House of Odin.
A master of magic
could bring three Jotuns into Asgard.
Loki's always been one for mischief,
but you're talking
about something else entirely.
Stop!
Am I cursed?
No.
What am I?
You're my son.
What more than that?
The Casket wasn't the only thing
you took from Jotunheim that day,
was it?
No.
In the aftermath of the battle,
I went into the temple
and I found a baby.
Small for a giant's offspring.
Abandoned, suffering, left to die.
Laufey's son.
Yes.
Why?
You were knee-deep in Jotun blood,
why would you take me?
You were an innocent child.
No. You took me for a purpose.
What was it?
Tell me!
I thought
we could unite our kingdoms one day.
Bring about an alliance,
bring about permanent peace.
Through you.
What?
But those plans no longer matter.
So I am no more
than another stolen relic,
locked up here
until you might have use of me.
Why do you twist my words?
You could have told me what I was
from the beginning,
why didn't you?
You're my son.
I wanted only to protect you
from the truth.
Because I'm the monster
parents tell their children about
at night?
- No, no.
- You know, it all makes sense now!
Why you favored Thor all these years!
Because no matter how much
you claim to love me,
you could never have a Frost Giant
sitting on the throne of Asgard!
Guards!
Guards, please, help!
How'd you get inside that cloud?
Also, how could you eat
an entire box of Pop-Tarts
and still be this hungry?
- This drink, I like it.
- I know. It's great, right?
Another!
Sorry, Izzy. Little accident.
- What was that?
- It was delicious. I want another.
- Well, you could have just said so.
- I just did.
- No, I mean, ask nicely.
- I meant no disrespect.
All right. Well, no more smashing.
Deal?
You have my word.
Good.
The usual, please, Izzy.
You missed all the excitement
out at the crater.
They're saying some kind
of satellite landed out in the desert.
Yeah, we were having
a good time with it
until the Feds showed up.
Excuse me.
Did you say there was a satellite crash?
Yeah.
Oh, my God. This is going on Facebook.
Smile.
What did it look like, the satellite?
I don't know anything about satellites,
but it was heavy.
I mean, nobody could lift it.
They said it was radioactive.
I had my hands all over it.
Which way?
50 miles west of here.
Well, I wouldn't waste my time!
Looked like the whole Army
was coming when we left.
Dumbass!
Where are you going?
- 50 miles west of here.
- Why?
- To get what belongs to me.
- Oh, so you own a satellite now?
It's not what they say it is.
Well, whatever it is,
the government seems to think
it's theirs.
So, you just intend to go in there
and take it?
Yes.
If you take me there now,
I'll tell you everything you wish to know.
- Everything?
- Yes.
All the answers you seek will be yours
once I reclaim Mjolnir.
Myeu-muh? What's Myeu-muh?
Can I have a word, Jane?
Please don't do this.
You saw what I saw last night.
This is no coincidence.
We have to find out what's in that crater.
But I'm not talking about the crater,
I'm talking about him.
- But he's promising us the answers.
- He's delusional.
Listen to what he's saying.
He's talking about Mjolnir
and Thor and Bifrost.
It's the stories I grew up with as a child.
I'm just going to drive him. That's it.
He's dangerous, Jane.
I'm sorry, but I can't take you.
Then this is where we say goodbye.
Um...
Thank you?
Jane Foster,
Erik Selvig,
Darcy,
farewell.
All right.
Back to work.
Hey!
That's my stuff!
What the hell is going on here?
Ms. Foster,
I'm Agent Coulson with S.H.I.E.L.D.
Is that supposed to mean something
to me?
- You can't do this!
- Jane!
Jane, this is a lot more serious
than you realize. Let it go.
Let it go? This is my life.
We're investigating a security threat.
We need to appropriate your records
and all your atmospheric data.
By "appropriate," do you mean steal?
Here, this should
more than compensate you
for your trouble.
I can't just buy replacements
at Radio Shack,
I made most of this equipment myself!
Then I'm sure you can do it again.
And I'm sure I can sue you
for violating my constitutional rights!
I'm sorry, Ms. Foster,
but we're the good guys.
So are we!
I'm on the verge of understanding
something extraordinary.
And everything I know
about this phenomenon
is either in this lab or in this book.
And you can't just take this away... Hey!
Jane! Easy! Easy. Jane...
Thank you for your cooperation.
Years of research,
gone.
They even took my iPod.
What about the backups?
They took our backups.
They took the backups of our backups.
They were extremely thorough.
I just downloaded, like,
30 songs onto there.
Could you please stop with your iPod?
Who are these people?
I knew this scientist.
The pioneer in gamma radiation.
S.H.I.E.L.D. showed up
and he wasn't heard from again.
They're not gonna do that to us.
I'm gonna get everything back.
Come on, please.
Let me contact one of my colleagues.
He's had some dealings
with these people before.
I'll e-mail him and maybe he can help.
They took your laptop, too.
Allfather,
we must speak with you urgently.
My friends.
Where's Odin?
Father has fallen into the Odinsleep.
Mother fears
he may never awaken again.
We would speak with her.
She has refused to leave
my father's bedside.
You can bring your urgent matter to me.
Your king.
My King, we would ask
that you end Thor's banishment.
My first command
cannot be to undo the Allfather's last.
We're on the brink of war
with Jotunheim.
Our people need a sense of continuity,
in order to feel safe
in these difficult times.
All of us must stand together
for the good of Asgard.
Yes, of course.
- Good. Then you will wait for my word.
- If I may
beg the indulgence of Your Majesty
to perhaps reconsider...
We're done!
I need a horse!
We don't have horses.
Just dogs, cats, birds...
Then give me one of those
large enough to ride.
Hey, you still need a lift?
I've never done anything like this before.
Have you ever done
anything like this before?
Many times.
But you're brave to do it.
Well, they just stole
my entire life's work.
I don't really have much left to lose.
Yeah, but you're clever.
Far more clever than anyone else
in this realm.
"Realm"? "Realm"?
- You think me strange.
- Yeah, I do.
Good strange or bad strange?
I'm not quite sure yet.
I'm sorry.
But who are you?
Really?
You'll see soon enough.
You promised me answers.
What you seek, it's a bridge.
Like an Einstein-Rosen Bridge?
More like a Rainbow Bridge.
God, I hope you're not crazy.
I never get used to seeing him like this.
He's put it off for so long now,
that I fear...
How long will it last?
I don't know. This time it's different.
We were unprepared.
So why did he lie?
He kept the truth from you
so that you would never feel different.
You are our son, Loki,
and we, your family.
We mustn't lose hope
that your father will return to us.
And your brother.
What hope is there for Thor?
There's always a purpose
to everything your father does.
That's no satellite crash!
They would have hauled
the wreckage away,
they wouldn't have built a city around it.
- You're going to need this.
- What? Wait, why?
Now stay here.
Once I have Mjolnir, I will return
the items they've stolen from you.
Deal?
No. Look what's down there.
You think you're just gonna walk in,
grab our stuff and walk out?
No. I'm going to fly out.
Sir, feed from the keyhole
can barely penetrate the cloud cover.
Tech's barely working as it is,
with all the interference
that thing's giving off.
And we've got a commercial aircraft
coming right over us.
Southwest Airlines, flight 5434.
Reroute it like all the others.
Hold a sec.
We've got something outside the fence,
west side.
Delancey, Jackson.
West side perimeter Go check it out.
There it is.
Delancey, Jackson. Report.
Agent down.
We've got a perimeter breach.
You've reached Dr Erik Selvig.
Please leave me a message.
Hi, Erik, it's me. Don't worry, I'm fine,
but just in case
you don't hear from me in the next hour,
just come by the crater site
and try and find me, okay?
I did exactly what you told me not to.
I'm sorry.
So sorry. Bye.
Bravo quadrant, move!
Entering south tunnel!
Negative, negative.
I have no comms.
Target sighted, east tunnel!
I need eyes up high, with a gun.
Moving north!
What have we got?
There's a massive
electromagnetic surge
coming off that thing.
Systems are barely coping.
Barton? Talk to me.
You want me to slow him down, sir?
Or are you sending in more guys
for him to beat up?
I'll let you know.
You're big.
Fought bigger.
Better call it, Coulson,
'cause I'm starting to root for this guy.
Last chance, sir.
Wait. I want to see this.
All right, show's over.
Ground units, move in.
He committed a crime. He's in jail!
I can't just leave him there!
Why?
You didn't see what I saw!
Look!
Look, it's Myeu-muh.
Where'd you find this?
The children's section.
I just wanted to show you
how silly his story was.
But you're the one
who's always pushing me
to chase down every possibility,
every alternative!
I'm talking about science, not magic!
Well, magic's just science
that we don't understand yet.
- Arthur C. Clarke.
- Who wrote science fiction.
- A precursor to science fact!
- In some cases, yeah.
Well, if there is
an Einstein-Rosen Bridge,
then there's something
on the other side.
And advanced beings
could have crossed it!
Jane.
A primitive culture like the Vikings
might have worshipped them as deities.
Yes! Yes, exactly. Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
You made my men,
some of the most
highly trained professionals in the world,
look like a bunch of minimum-wage
mall cops.
that's hurtful.
In my experience, it takes someone
who's received similar training
to do what you did to them.
Why don't you tell me
where you received your training?
Pakistan? Chechnya? Afghanistan?
No, you strike me
more as the soldier of fortune type.
Where was it? South Africa?
Certain groups pay very well
for a good mercenary like you.
Who are you?
One way or another,
we find out what we need to know.
We're good at that.
Don't go anywhere.
Loki! What are you doing here?
I had to see you.
What's happened?
Tell me. Is it Jotunheim?
Let me explain to Father.
Father is dead.
What?
Your banishment,
the threat of a new war,
it was too much for him to bear.
You mustn't blame yourself.
I know that you loved him.
I tried to tell him so,
but he wouldn't listen.
It was so cruel
to put the hammer within your reach,
knowing that you could never lift it.
The burden of the throne
has fallen to me now.
Can I come home?
The truce with Jotunheim
is conditional upon your exile.
- Yes, but couldn't we find a way...
- And Mother has forbidden your return.
This is goodbye, Brother.
I'm so sorry.
No.
I am sorry.
Thank you for coming here.
Farewell.
Goodbye.
Good bye?
I just got back.
Sir?
He's got a visitor.
His name is Donald Blake?
Dr. Donald Blake.
You have dangerous coworkers,
Dr. Selvig.
He was distraught when he found out
that you've taken all our research.
That was years of his life, gone!
You can understand
how a man could go off like that.
A big, faceless organization like yours
coming in with their
jackbooted thugs and...
That's how he put it.
That still doesn't explain
how he managed
to tear through our security.
Steroids! He's a bit of a fitness nut.
Sir?
It says here that he's an M.D.
Well, he is! Or he was.
He switched careers
and became a physicist.
A brilliant physicist.
He's a wonderful man.
He's a man in pain.
Oh, Donny, Donny, Donny!
There you are. You're gonna be all right.
I'm taking you home now.
Dr. Selvig!
Just keep him away from the bars.
I will!
- Where are we going?
- To get a drink.
Follow them.
You know, I had it all backwards.
I had it all wrong.
It's not a bad thing finding out
that you don't have all the answers.
You start asking the right questions.
For the first time in my life,
I have no idea what I'm supposed to do.
Anyone who's ever going to
find his way in this world
has to start by admitting
he doesn't know where the hell he is.
Thank you for what you've done.
No, don't thank me. I only did it for Jane.
Her father and I
taught at university together.
He was a good man.
He never listened.
Neither did I.
My father
was trying to teach me something,
but I was too stupid to see it.
I don't know if you're delusional
or if you're pulling some kind of con,
I don't care.
I just care about her.
I've seen the way she looks at you.
I swear to you, I mean her no harm.
Good.
In that case, I'll buy you another round,
and you leave town tonight.
Two boilermakers.
Kill him.
After all I've done for you?
So you're the one
who showed us the way into Asgard.
That was just a bit of fun, really.
To ruin my brother's big day.
And to protect the realm
from his idiotic rule for a while longer.
I will hear you.
I will conceal you
and a handful of your soldiers,
lead you into Odin's chambers,
and you can slay him where he lies.
Why not kill him yourself?
I suspect that the Asgardians
would not take kindly
to a king who had murdered
his predecessor.
Once Odin is dead,
I will return the Casket to you
and you can return Jotunheim to all its...
Glory.
Accept.
What troubles you, Gatekeeper?
I turned my gaze upon you in Jotunheim,
but could neither see you nor hear you.
You were shrouded from me,
like the Frost Giants
that entered this realm.
Perhaps your senses have weakened
after your many years of service.
Or perhaps someone has found a way
to hide that
which he does not wish me to see.
You have great power, Heimdall.
Did Odin ever fear you?
- No.
- And why is that?
Because he is my king
and I am sworn to obey him.
He was your king
and you're sworn to obey me now.
Yes?
Yes.
Then you will open the Bifrost to no one
until I have repaired the damage
that my brother has done.
Oh, my God. Is he okay?
He's fine. Not injured at all.
I'm sorry, my friend.
- What happened?
- We drank, we fought,
he made his ancestors proud.
Put him on the bed.
I still don't think
you're the God of Thunder.
But you ought to be.
Are these your chambers?
It's more of a temporary living situation.
I'm sorry. I don't usually have guests.
Actually, I never have guests.
That's not the right place for it.
I'm sorry.
Can we go outside?
Yes, of course.
I come up here sometimes
when I can't sleep
or I'm trying to reconcile particle data,
or when Darcy's driving me crazy.
I come up here a lot, actually,
now that I think about it.
I'm really glad you're safe.
You've been very kind to me,
and I've been far less grateful
than you deserve.
Well, I hit you with my car
a couple times,
so I think that kind of evens things out.
Perhaps I had it coming.
Oh, my God!
I don't believe it!
It was all I could get back.
I'm sorry it's not as much as I promised.
No, no, this is great! This is...
I don't have to start from scratch now.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
S.H.l.E.L.D.
Whatever they are,
they're gonna do
everything in their power
to make sure this research
never sees the light of day.
No, Jane.
Listen to me. You must not give up.
- You must finish what you've started.
- Why?
Because you're right.
Here, look.
Your ancestors called it magic,
and you call it science.
Well, I come from a place
where they're one and the same thing.
What is that?
My father explained it to me like this,
that your world
is one of the Nine Realms
of the Cosmos,
linked to each other
by the branches of Yggdrasil,
the Worlds Tree.
Now you see it every day
without realizing.
The images glimpsed through...
What did you call it?
This Hooble Telescope.
- Hubble.
- Hubble Telescope.
Tell me more.
So, the Nine Realms.
Now, there is Midgard, which is Earth.
This is Alfheim.
Vanaheim. Jotunheim.
And Asgard.
And that's where I come from.
Thank you, Jane.
Our dearest friend banished,
Loki on the throne,
Asgard on the brink of war,
yet you've managed to consume
four wild boar,
six pheasant, a side of beef,
and two casks of ale. Shame on you.
Don't you care?
Do not mistake my appetite for apathy!
Stop it, both of you!
Stop.
- We all know what we have to do.
- We must go.
We must find Thor.
It's treason.
To hell with treason, it's suicide.
Thor would do the same for us.
Now shush.
Heimdall might be watching.
Heimdall demands your presence.
We're doomed.
You would defy the commands of Loki,
our king,
break every oath you
have taken as warriors,
and commit treason to bring Thor back?
- Yes.
- Good.
So you'll help us?
I am bound by honor to our king.
I cannot open the bridge to you.
Complicated fellow, isn't he?
Now what do we do?
Look!
- What the hell was that?
- I don't know, sir.
We got massive energy readings
out of nowhere
and then they just disappeared.
15 miles due northwest.
Let's go take a look.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- You're very welcome.
Base to Team 2,
we've got activity outside the town.
Stay on your target.
Ensure my brother does not return.
Destroy everything.
Mom?
Is there a Renaissance Fair in town?
Call it in.
Yeah.
Base, we've got Xena, Jackie Chan
and Robin Hood.
It's a beautiful theory, Jane.
But you won't be able to convince
the scientific community of any of it.
Not without hard evidence.
Found you!
My friends!
This is good! This is good.
I don't believe it.
Oh, excuse me.
Lady Sif and the Warriors Three.
My friends,
I've never been happier to see anyone.
But you should not have come.
We're here to take you home.
You know I can't go home.
My father
is dead because of me.
And I must remain in exile.
Thor,
your father still lives.
Tell me, Loki,
how did you get the Jotuns into Asgarol?
You think the Bifrost is the only way
in and out of this realm?
There are secret paths
between the worlds
to which even you, with all your gifts,
are blind.
But I have need of them no longer,
now that I am king.
And I say, for your act of treason,
you are relieved of your duties
as Gatekeeper,
and no longer citizen of Asgard.
Then I need no longer obey you.
Get somebody from Linguistics
down here.
Was somebody else coming?
Is that one of Stark's?
I don't know.
The guy never tells me anything.
Hello.
You are using
unregistered weapons technology.
Identify yourself
Here we go.
Incoming!
Jane, you have to leave.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm staying here.
Thor's going to fight with us!
My friends,
I'm just a man. I'll only be in the way,
or worse, get one of you killed.
But I can help
get these people to safety.
Well, if you're staying, then so am I.
- We'll need some time.
- You'll have it!
Okay, move it, people!
Everybody out! Use the back door.
Go, hurry! You can eat later.
Keep it distracted.
For Asgard!
Fall back!
Go. Now. Run!
Sif. Sif, you've done all you can.
No. I will die a warrior's death.
Stories will be told of this day.
Live, and tell those stories yourself.
Now go.
You must return to Asgard.
You have to stop Loki.
What about you?
Do not worry, my friends. I have a plan.
Come on.
We need to fall back. Come on.
Wait!
What's he doing?
Brother,
whatever I have done to wrong you,
whatever I have done
to lead you to do this,
I am truly sorry.
But these people are innocent.
Taking their lives will gain you nothing.
So take mine
and end this.
No.
It's over.
No. it's not over.
I mean, you're safe.
We're safe.
It's over.
No.
We're spiking.
Levels increase!
Whosoever holds this hammer,
if he be worthy,
shall possess the power of Thor.
Jane!
- No. No. No!
- Come!
Oh. My. God.
So, is this how you normally look?
More or less.
It's a good look.
We must go to the Bifrost site.
I would have words with my brother.
Excuse me!
Donald?
I don't think
you've been completely honest with me.
Know this, Son of Coul.
You and I, we fight for the same cause,
the protection of this world.
From this day forward,
you can count me as your ally
if you return the items
you have taken from Jane.
- Stolen.
- Borrowed.
Of course,
you can have your equipment back.
You're gonna need it
to continue your research.
Would you like to see
the bridge we spoke of?
Sure.
Wait, I need to debrief you!
Welcome to Asgard.
Heimdall, open the Bifrost.
Heimdall?
Heimdall!
He doesn't answer.
Then we are stranded.
Heimdall!
If you can hear me, we need you now!
Heimdall! We need you now!
Heimdall!
I must go back to Asgard,
but I give you my word,
I will return for you.
Deal?
Deal.
Get him to the healing room!
Leave my brother to me.
It's said
you can still hear and see
what transpires around you.
I hope it's true,
so that you may know
your death came at the hand
of Laufey.
And your death came
by the son of Odin.
Loki!
You saved him!
I swear to you, Mother,
that they will pay for what
they've done today.
Loki.
Thor!
I knew you'd return to us.
Why don't you tell her
how you sent the Destroyer
to kill our friends, to kill me?
What?
Why, it must have been enforcing
Father's last command.
You're a talented liar, Brother.
Always have been.
It's good to have you back.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have to destroy Jotunheim.
You can't stop it.
The Bifrost will build until
it rips Jotunheim apart.
Jane?
Why have you done this?
To prove to Father
that I am the worthy son.
When he wakes,
I will have saved his life.
I will have destroyed that
race of monsters.
And I will be true heir to the throne!
You can't kill an entire race!
Why not?
And what is this newfound love
for the Frost Giants?
You could have killed them all
with your bare hands.
- I've changed.
- So have I.
Now fight me.
I never wanted the throne!
I only ever wanted to be your equal.
I will not fight you, Brother!
I'm not your brother.
I never was.
Loki, this is madness.
Is it madness?
Is it?
Come on. What happened to you
on Earth that turned you so soft?
Don't tell me it was that woman.
Oh!
It was!
Well, maybe, when we're finished here,
I'll pay her a visit myself!
Thor!
Brother, please.
Enough!
Look at you,
the Mighty Thor,
with all your strength,
and what good does it do you now, huh?
Do you hear me, Brother?
There's nothing you can do!
What are you doing?
If you destroy the bridge,
you'll never see her again!
Forgive me, Jane.
I could have done it, Father!
I could have done it!
For you!
For all of us!
NO, Loki.
Loki, no.
No!
No.
it's gone.
And then, with a mighty bellow,
I flew into the giant metal creature
and laid him low!
Is that another way of saying
you fell on your huge ass?
As a matter of fact, falling
was a tactic lulling the Destroyer...
My Queen, I'm so sorry for your loss.
How is he?
He mourns for his brother.
And...
He misses hen
The mortal.
You'll be a wise king.
There will never be
a wiser king than you.
Or a better father.
I have much to learn.
I know that now.
Someday, perhaps,
I shall make you proud.
You've already made me proud.
So Earth is lost to us.
No.
There is always hope.
Can you see her?
Yes.
I have the particle detectors!
Darcy, do you have the S.H.I.E.L.D.
satellite codes?
Yeah. Have you seen my taser?
How is she?
In the car. Come on, Jane!
She searches for you.
Dr. Selvig.
So you're the man behind all this?
It's quite a labyrinth.
I was thinking
they're taking me down here to kill me.
I've been hearing
about the New Mexico situation.
Your work has impressed a lot of people
who are much smarter than I am.
I have a lot to work with.
The Foster Theory.
A gateway to another dimension.
It's unprecedented.
Isn't it?
Legend tells us one thing,
history, another.
But every now and then,
we find something that belongs to both.
What is it?
Power, Doctor.
If we can figure out how to tap it,
maybe unlimited power.
Well, I guess that's worth a look.